[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c770", "question": "What \"L\"-word is the name for the family of plants including the peanut and soybean?", "answer": "Legume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf1", "question": "Who wrote \"Slaughterhouse Five\"?", "answer": "Kurt Vonnegut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecae4a7790ded87bb38fd8c", "question": "Who was the leading goalscorer for SKC in 2012?", "answer": "Kei Kamara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f9", "question": "Who wrote the novels \"The Deceiver\" and \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941f", "question": "Which fairytale princess likes sushi in the movie \"Shrek\"?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b0", "question": "Simon & Simon, from the TV show by the same name, were in what business?", "answer": "Private Detectives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e91", "question": "What movie did the villain Norman Bates appear in?", "answer": "Psycho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909ccedbb53d1af658864e5", "question": "What branch of Christianity introduced the Advent calendar?", "answer": "German Lutherans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23a", "question": "What do Vanilla Ice, Willow Smith, Rob Schneider, John Candy and Michael Landon all have in common?", "answer": "They were all born on Halloween", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c600", "question": "What is the closest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925a", "question": "Which town's businesses include the \"I Can't Believe It's a Law Firm\" and \"J.R.R. Toykins\"?", "answer": "Springfield's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339497", "question": "How many children do Daniel and Miranda have in the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bf", "question": "How many hours are there in 1 week?", "answer": "168 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b640", "question": "What comes out of a hawsehole?", "answer": "Ship's cable", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a7", "question": "What baseball player was nicknamed \"Joltin' Joe\" and the \"Yankee Clipper\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a029", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who did Peter force to become a professional boxer?", "answer": "Lois", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a973861d1b4d384d5d681", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"travelator\"?", "answer": "Moving walkway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b912", "question": "\"Benjamins\" is slang for what denomination of US currency?", "answer": "$100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23c", "question": "What royal subject married Marie Antoinette?", "answer": "Louis XVI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012152463c99d48cd169ae7", "question": "What did Einstein reportedly do to stay focused?", "answer": "Play music -- His wife Elsa said that when he was struggling with a theory he would play a few chords on the piano to focus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6f", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Tommy\"?", "answer": "Roger Daltry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a66", "question": "What was the name of the short-lived 2002 sitcom which starred Andy Richter in the title role?", "answer": "Andy Richter Controls the Universe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f2", "question": "Who played the part of \"Bluebottle\" in a popular radio comedy series?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c841", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the duct of Wirsung?", "answer": "The pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b730", "question": "What variety of beans is used to prepare Boston baked beans?", "answer": "Navy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a553", "question": "Which three US states have shorelines along Lake Superior?", "answer": "Michigan, Minnesota, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f8", "question": "What is the fear of microbes known as?", "answer": "Microbiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8eff201dd7bf43be5e7f7", "question": "Which beauty supply company started out selling dental supplies?", "answer": "OPI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a13620565ad31a57c7a1", "question": "What is the lowest natural point on Earth?", "answer": "The Challenger Deep", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11e", "question": "What famous animal character called \"Skull Island\" home?", "answer": "King Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab34a0b8cce1e6fda7044", "question": "What do you call filo pastry stuffed with chopped nuts and honey, or syrup?", "answer": "Baklava", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6f", "question": "What was Rod Stewart's first #1 song?", "answer": "Maggie May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0e8f469bb8041d07a061", "question": "What is a word having same spelling but different sound and meaning?", "answer": "Heteronym", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f8", "question": "Who was the second Toronto Blue Jay player to lead the American league in home runs?", "answer": "Fred McGriff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe767d3eec85e375820b297", "question": "Which Canadian province produces the most maple syrup?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a509", "question": "Which country was formerly known as East Pakistan?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958b", "question": "Who plays the role of Sarah Jordan in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Scarlett Johansson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339492", "question": "Who directed the 1999 movie \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Frank Darabont", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b709", "question": "What is Santa Claus more commonly called in Britain?", "answer": "Father Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb1", "question": "Who was the father of Cleopatra's twins?", "answer": "Mark Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d36", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Reading Gaol\"?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdabd760b8cce1e6fda7063", "question": "What meat is the primary ingredient in Booyah, a thick stew?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cc", "question": "Which 1947 film, starring Cary Grant and Loretta Young was directed by Henry Koster?", "answer": "The Bishop's Wife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5e", "question": "Which country was known as British Honduras prior to 1973?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ac", "question": "What children's book hero did the cruel Dursleys bring up after an evil wizard killed his parents?", "answer": "Harry Potter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7beaa2b316f4693fb6791", "question": "The word \"squash\" comes from a Native American word meaning what?", "answer": "From the Narragansett word \"askutasquash\" which means \"eaten raw or uncooked\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f1", "question": "Who painted the cover art for the 1993 Billy Joel album \"River of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2f", "question": "What 1984 song by Prince was his first to hit #1 on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "When Doves Cry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f8", "question": "What explorer disappeared in 1928 while on a rescue mission for survivors of the crashed airship \"Italia\"?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5a3f6ce05a3942286e0b", "question": "\"Life is Beautiful\" has been named one of the top-five favorite films of which prominent figure?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6648c52a821ff76ae8af2", "question": "Besides Pompeii, what other ancient Italian city was engulfed by Mount Vesuvius?", "answer": "Herculaneum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636f3c967692ea851899b5", "question": "The average American will eat 35,000 what in a lifetime?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d48", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Dragonfly\"?", "answer": "Alison Lohman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e1", "question": "Who sent the 1884 cable that said \"I will not accept if nominated and will not serve if elected\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a958", "question": "Which European country replaced the Pound with the Euro?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bca", "question": "According to legend, where did the Norse gods live?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be23", "question": "What color M&M was retired to make way for blue M&Ms in 1995?", "answer": "Tan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bc", "question": "What natural \"Wonder of the World\" lies off the east coast of Australia?", "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03e6caa1c9af2684d79a4", "question": "What is the common name for CH3COOH?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977c", "question": "What is the name of Kane's private estate in Citizen Kane?", "answer": "Xanadu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff3", "question": "What is the correct name for a virgin cow?", "answer": "Heifer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6b", "question": "What is a series containing seven instalments called?", "answer": "A Heptalogy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b834", "question": "How many times are Mexican refried beans fried?", "answer": "Once", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892b", "question": "Thor is the son of which Norse god?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a8ee90aac110e4167093", "question": "What French beverage is made by mixing apple juice with apple brandy and aging it in barrels?", "answer": "Pommeau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ce", "question": "Who wrote \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Neil Gaiman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015eb13fe83fe1f2a824bf7", "question": "Who did the German Nazi regime replace Santa Claus with?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4c", "question": "What author's headstone includes the phrase \"Quoth the Raven, Nevermore\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allen Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971e", "question": "In the classic movie \"Animal House\", what was the name of the college?", "answer": "Faber College", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d1195b4fea7fe947a2228e", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac0", "question": "Lake Erie contains an artificial reef made from the pieces of which sports stadium demolished in 1996?", "answer": "Cleveland Municipal Stadium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ccf7a10b37b32637bdc44bf", "question": "What is it called when the liquid vapor pressure equals to the pressure of the gas above it?", "answer": "Boiling Point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe938846bd93ce3a4e5f686", "question": "What aquatic biologist is widely credited with helping launch the environmental movement?", "answer": "Rachel Carson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69f1720565ad31a57c78a", "question": "The first woman to run for president chose whom as her running mate?", "answer": "Fredrick Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff56e1cf6db9ac4808cea", "question": "Where is the mythological birthplace of the Incas?", "answer": "Isla del Sol, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc168ec223966ae8f886a", "question": "Which musical group originally begged the Postman for a letter?", "answer": "The Marvelettes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a5527e3e1c6f9840ba3196", "question": "The telephone country code 82 would connect you with which country?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5ef46ce05a3942286e3c", "question": "Who had a hit song with the theme from the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ray Parker, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6220775fa611bce67cf", "question": "What was the original name of Chicago's Willis Tower?", "answer": "Sears Tower -- Sears Tower, the former home to Sears Roebuck and Company, was the tallest building in the world from 1973 to 1998.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c570", "question": "What blood vessels carry blood towards the heart?", "answer": "Veins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ed7f9a72b906b34e3cec", "question": "Who discovered the mathematical system of logarithms?", "answer": "John Napier", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012125e63c99d48cd169ae2", "question": "\"Prehistory\" refers to the era before what?", "answer": "Writing -- The Prehistoric Era lasted from around 12,000 to 3,000 B.C.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e802f7de59ea584496fe9a", "question": "Which fashion designer is popular for his \"Space Age\" look?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b212", "question": "Who was assassinated by Dan White?", "answer": "Harvey Milk and George Moscone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7f", "question": "How many lanes does an olympic standard swimming pool have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0aa", "question": "Who won an oscar for her role in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e98", "question": "What movie did the villain Mrs. Danvers appear in?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d3", "question": "What is permanently-frozen subsoil called?", "answer": "Permafrost", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff511c7ff04d658268c92ca", "question": "How did Mary Ludwig Hays earn the nickname \"Molly Pitcher\"?", "answer": "During the Battle of Monmouth, she attended to the Revolutionary soldiers by\u00a0bringing them water, often under heavy fire.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0c", "question": "In which US state is the Catalina Island located?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bc", "question": "U2's David Evans is better known by which nickname?", "answer": "The Edge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12ceae39efa6330e0fec8", "question": "Hawaii's tallest mountain is on which island?", "answer": "Hawai'i", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babb", "question": "What was the combined points scored in Super Bowl II?", "answer": "47", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df3", "question": "What movie's theme was remixed in 2005 into Crazy Frog's biggest hit?", "answer": "Beverly Hills Cop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339412", "question": "On the \"Abbey Road\" album cover, which member of the Beatles is on the far left?", "answer": "George Harrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4be", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Tajikistan and Russia?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6bac8fb6c85e9e634ff52", "question": "What is the name for the group of men who elect a Pope?", "answer": "College of Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80d", "question": "Easter Island, home to mysterious giant stone faces, is owned by what South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb74", "question": "An amendment to the US Constitution must be ratified by what fraction of all the states?", "answer": "75%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e86c38e4e5d4832e630a", "question": "In the Bible, whose vineyard did King Ahab wish to acquire?", "answer": "Naboth's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd51", "question": "The Hugo Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Science fiction", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5941257abab1e6f9796f1b54", "question": "Which character is always trying to steal the secret Krusty Krab Recipe on \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Plankton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a08", "question": "For what movie did Dan Aykroyd receive an Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Driving Miss Daisy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd5a27e83c707845b2163", "question": "What tool does Andy use in shaping his chess pieces in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A rock blanket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a27", "question": "Which great Renaissance artist designed the dome of St. Peter's Basilica in Rome?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7facff048f679a45ac14", "question": "What poison is found in apple seeds?", "answer": "Cyanide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339128", "question": "Who composed the 1877 opera \"Samson and Delilah\"?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Saens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008d9ccf842fa4c4ba96ab", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Oedipus marry?", "answer": "Jocasta, his mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f9", "question": "Which UK band had a 1974 hit with \"Billy Don't Be A Hero\"?", "answer": "Paper Lace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff08fd2e662d71a53650fb2", "question": "Which philosophical movement helped inspire the American Revolution?", "answer": "The Enlightenment -- It included great leaps in philosophical thought \u2014 including ideas about democracy, the social contract, and freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d41", "question": "What was Dutch painter Rembrandt's full name?", "answer": "Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d8", "question": "What Jane Austen book has many parallels with \"Bridget Jones's Diary\" including the main male character?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa5", "question": "Which oil rig exploded in 1988 killing 167 people?", "answer": "Piper Alpha", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c580", "question": "What two colors are most often confused by people who are color blind?", "answer": "Red and green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a5", "question": "What is the hobby of autograph collecting called?", "answer": "Philography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a7", "question": "What is Falaka?", "answer": "Feet beating", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a465", "question": "What countries form the United Kingdom?", "answer": "England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa86973838c5c8a417f3d", "question": "What common kitchen ingredient is crucial to the human body\u2019s chemistry?", "answer": "Salt (The human body contains many types of salts, but the primary is NaCL, or sodium chloride, also known as common table salt.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c680", "question": "Organic chemistry is centered around what two elements?", "answer": "Carbon and Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66555a5bfecdd737e085e", "question": "What was the costliest earthquake in U.S. history?", "answer": "Northridge (1994)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7fa2596a59cbdfbd3bd", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae45", "question": "Of what nationality was the explorer Ponce de Leon?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64e", "question": "What media personality was once a speechwriter for Richard Nixon?", "answer": "Ben Stein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7a04ff048f679a45abe5", "question": "Where is the uvula located?", "answer": "In the throat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b484", "question": "What year was actor Arthur Stanley Jefferson born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f49001dd7bf43be5e823", "question": "What is America's oldest brewery?", "answer": "Yuengling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4b", "question": "What color is the complimentary color opposite of Violet on the color wheel?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a929", "question": "Where is the Boxing Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Canastota, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2e", "question": "What company bought naming rights to the Florida Suncoast Dome in 1996?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c084877e98cb9777896d", "question": "What is the primary mountain range in Iran?", "answer": "Zagros Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358df35db0d66a186cb565", "question": "Burt Reynolds played the role of who on the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Blacksmith Quint Asper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfe639dc5ec6cd98a832a", "question": "Which character is pregnant at the beginning of The Grapes of Wrath?", "answer": "Rose of Sharon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e803cade59ea584496fe9f", "question": "The novel \"The Great Dog Robbery\" is better known under what title?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5afad9cf430e050a5df0d115", "question": "Who were the first people in the world to eat popcorn?", "answer": "The Natives in the Americas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f4", "question": "What condiment is Lea & Perrins most famous for?", "answer": "Worcestershire Sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c084", "question": "What is the fear of lice called?", "answer": "Pediculophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a614", "question": "What is the capital of Nigeria?", "answer": "Abuja", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27d", "question": "What was in Kathryn's crucifix in the 1999 film \"Cruel Intentions\"?", "answer": "Cocaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbf7c003d27d341092bd7", "question": "Which is the only country to have its own official scent?", "answer": "Lithuania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601369741381754895396370", "question": "Which American poet won a Grammy for writing a Johnny Cash song?", "answer": "Shel Silverstein -- Best known for children's literature, he also wrote Johnny Cash's country hit, \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339789", "question": "What two characters from \"The Little Rascals\" are named after plants?", "answer": "Alfalfa and Buckwheat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb7", "question": "What made-up expletive is \"Battlestar Galactica's\" dirty word of choice?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f0", "question": "Which actress was jailed in 1982 for tax evasion?", "answer": "Sophia Loren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c90", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Sunnydale, California?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25a", "question": "In what country did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f8", "question": "In the movie \"Pulp Fiction\", what is the name of the restaurant Mia brings Vincent to?", "answer": "Jack-Rabbit Slim's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3fc", "question": "Who was James Garfield's vice president?", "answer": "Chester A. Arthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339287", "question": "In season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" what coach lost all but one player in the first week but kept until final 3?", "answer": "Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2a", "question": "Which of his ten fingers is God using to give Adam life on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "His index finger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecaec9e790ded87bb38fd90", "question": "In the 1984 film, \"Purple Rain\", who did The Kid tell to purify herself in the waters of Lake Minnetonka?", "answer": "Apollonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b849", "question": "What is the highest hand in straight poker?", "answer": "A royal flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d8", "question": "By what name is Theodore Kaczynski better known?", "answer": "The Unabomber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600240d14be4723ccac22169", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dances with Wolves\"?", "answer": "Michael Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf54", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 17th May?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd8a87e83c707845b2177", "question": "Who is the only prison inmate to admit that he is guilty in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c5", "question": "What is the official state animal of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b2", "question": "What does LD50 stand for?", "answer": "Lethal Dose 50%, or Medium Lethal Dose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca51", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6c", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was known for the catchphrase \"Exit, Stage Left\" when dashing off?", "answer": "Snagglepuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c98", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Stuckeyville, Ohio?", "answer": "Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80d", "question": "What is the basic flavoring of Kahlua?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c6", "question": "What continent includes Iran?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb359eb2627b8fe95581be6", "question": "What nickname is printed on the official Wilson NFL football?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8ef1601dd7bf43be5e7f1", "question": "What measurement of time is used for Olympic swimming competitions?", "answer": "One millionth of a second", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071f333745b36be73039e9", "question": "What is Em Cypress' secret in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "She is a reviver", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c847fbde8045e48466d5", "question": "What kind of unique fur does a platypus have?", "answer": "As if it weren't an odd enough creature, the platypus' fur is bioluminescent, meaning they can glow in the dark.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa52", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritania?", "answer": "Nouakchott", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96c0e23c87fd04dd15e1f", "question": "What U.S. post office doesn't fly the American flag?", "answer": "B. Free Franklin Post Office in Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c925", "question": "What is a characteristic of a \"nimbus\" cloud?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909d291bb53d1af6588650b", "question": "What toy was Arnold Schwarzenegger after in the movie \"Jingle All the Way\"?", "answer": "Turbo-Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3c", "question": "Who founded the John Birch Society?", "answer": "Robert Welch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c446", "question": "How many chromosomes does a chicken have?", "answer": "78", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4dcf306d333868d34d6fd", "question": "Who won four gold medals in the 1936 Olympics, infuriating Adolf Hitler?", "answer": "Jessie Owens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e6", "question": "Which US president lived in Shadow Lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f77", "question": "What was Gladys Knight's backing band?", "answer": "The Pips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25eed16682715b82711cd1", "question": "Which European country strted colonizing Venezuela in 1522?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f4", "question": "What day is the Super Bowl always played on?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc122ec223966ae8f8865", "question": "The 1982 football game that birthed \"The Play\", was between which schools?", "answer": "Stanford and Berkeley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be63", "question": "What kind of farm is a formicarium?", "answer": "An ant farm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a09", "question": "Who played the first \"Tool Time Girl\" on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5c106ce05a3942286e1d", "question": "Which Disney film features the song \"When You Wish Upon a Star\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fe", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"catamaran\"?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd2", "question": "Who were the first people to separate copper from its ore?", "answer": "The Ancient Egyptians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4eac106d333868d34d75c", "question": "What was the first Nazi concentration camp?", "answer": "Dachau (Nohra opened in March 1933 as a re-education center. Dachau opened after and became a model for future death camps and is considered to be the first)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66be9a5bfecdd737e088b", "question": "What's the name of the punctuation that combines a question mark and an exclamation point?", "answer": "Interrobang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eaf96f83302ff91e46494", "question": "What are juvenile goats called?", "answer": "Kids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a7f720565ad31a57c7f1", "question": "What President\u2019s fondness for pork rinds made sales of the snack boom?", "answer": "George H. W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5922028ca4edfd43a087addf", "question": "How many strings are there on the \"Spanish Guitar\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b7f6364247bf200fb879", "question": "Which Russian chemist created the modern periodic table?", "answer": "Dmitri Mendeleev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d2", "question": "Which desert is the driest on earth?", "answer": "Atacama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fae", "question": "Who composed the music for the opera \"The Tales of Hoffman\"?", "answer": "Jacques Offenbach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989f", "question": "What movie is set in the year 2154 on the moon of Pandora?", "answer": "Avatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3ed658b5801b8f54a7fb1", "question": "From 1960 to 1965, which African country was a major area of Chinese political influence?", "answer": "Central African Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339353", "question": "For how many years was the \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\" on air?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d30", "question": "What novel is Aldous Huxley's fifth novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4ab6ce05a3942286eb7", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Jonsey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b879", "question": "In which city does the Tour de France end?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552fd3e1c6f9840ba319f", "question": "Which band released the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7c2dff048f679a45abf6", "question": "What was the first planet discovered by telescope?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b151", "question": "In what year did Charles Lindburgh make his historic non-stop solo flight across the Atlantic?", "answer": "1927", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339846", "question": "What TV family includes Gomez, Morticia, and Pugsley?", "answer": "Addams Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338daa", "question": "What object did photographer Andres Serrano place in a glass of his own urine in 1989?", "answer": "A crucifix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5efa93f1ccb363a2cbc52278", "question": "What is the largest landlocked county in England?", "answer": "Shropshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b269", "question": "Artist Bono shared Time's \"Man of the Year\" honors with what other man and his wife?", "answer": "Bill Gates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597742ce284458f1d7854422", "question": "What two Coaches on \"The Voice\" US have been on from season 1 through season 14?", "answer": "Blake Shelton and Adam Levine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e3", "question": "Grand Mesa is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580225415ba52ed6f0ab1", "question": "The TV show \"Soap\", was set in what fictional town?", "answer": "Dunn's River, Connecticut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5667a33a95c66dc4fe763", "question": "In the TV show, \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the family's cat?", "answer": "Snowball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c0c1877e98cb9777896e", "question": "What is the least populated continguous U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feccf49ec223966ae8f88b4", "question": "How does Jill Masterson die in \"Goldfinger\"?", "answer": "Her skin is painted gold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af15", "question": "President Abraham Lincoln was a member of which political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65e", "question": "When standing in sunlight, what vitamin does your body synthesize?", "answer": "D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea83f4ff048f679a45ac2e", "question": "What is the most common type of rock found on Earth's surface?", "answer": "Sedimentary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f7b6fe83fe1f2a824c25", "question": "Which Christmas carol became the first song ever to be broadcast from space?", "answer": "Astronauts Tome Stafford and Wally Schirra sang \"Jingle Bells\" from space on 16 December 1965.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339946", "question": "What are the names of Brian Wilson\u2019s two brothers in the original lineup of the Beach Boys.", "answer": "Carl and Dennis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfa", "question": "What's the meat in McDonald's original recipe for Egg McMuffins?", "answer": "Canadian bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937986bd93ce3a4e5f671", "question": "Dystychiphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Accidents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede5766ce05a3942286ded", "question": "What was the first cooking show on television, hosted by James Beard in 1946, called?", "answer": "\"I Love to Eat\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b16", "question": "What actor did Melanie Griffith marry, and divorce, twice?", "answer": "Don Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c588", "question": "What is an adult male polar bear referred to as?", "answer": "A boar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eaf51f83302ff91e46492", "question": "What is the stage name of Roberta Joan Anderson?", "answer": "Joni Mitchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a1a5cad1ec93f27df778", "question": "In English-speaking countries, what is Rauchbier typically referred to as?", "answer": "Smoked beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af94", "question": "Who popularized the Christmas tree in England in the 19th century?", "answer": "Prince Albert", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008aafcf842fa4c4ba9692", "question": "Who released the 1979 song \"Rock 'n' Roll High School\"?", "answer": "The Ramones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c5", "question": "What Irish city's name is Gaelic for \"black pool\"?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6e", "question": "What can be a font, architectural style or novel type?", "answer": "Gothic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1cf0c7bd84c0ea43ad43e", "question": "The song \"The Obvious Child\" was a hit in 1990 for which singer?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8ce8d94b094db915830a8", "question": "What did the letters \u201cC\u201d and \u201cN\u201d originally stand for in Toronto\u2019s CN Tower", "answer": "Canadian National", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995f", "question": "Who played Angela Bower on the TV show \"Who\u2019s the Boss\"?", "answer": "Judith Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b7c3e662d71a53651017", "question": "What is the occupation of \"Fahrenheit 451\" protagonist Guy Montag?", "answer": "Fireman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c754", "question": "What layer of the atmosphere is closest to the earth?", "answer": "The Troposphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2599031a458464a93c46d", "question": "In the US South, ground hominy is more popularly know as what?", "answer": "Grits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600b87ba1d8c1817608d53ea", "question": "How many letters are there in the German alphabet?", "answer": "30", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c7", "question": "What was the original name of the game Pac-Man prior to its release?", "answer": "Puck Man", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab979f86faa38a764be52a", "question": "What is the Wankel engine typically referred to as?", "answer": "Rotary engine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339567", "question": "What year saw the release of the made-for-TV classic, Frosty the Snowman?", "answer": "1969", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2102531a458464a93c43c", "question": "What classic novel was originally published with the title \"Fiesta\" in the U.K.?", "answer": "\"The Sun Also Rises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d1e32596a59cbdfbd388", "question": "The film \"The Color of Money\" reprised the role of Edward \"Fast Eddie\" Felson from which earlier film?", "answer": "The Hustler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef6", "question": "Which Saint is said to have carried his own head for six miles after his death?", "answer": "Saint Denis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdcefec223966ae8f88fa", "question": "Which Christmas song was the second piece of music broadcast on the radio?", "answer": "\"O Holy Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb73", "question": "The card game \"Penguin\" is a variation of what other card game?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad1", "question": "What name is shared by America's first Naval hero and the bass player for Led Zeppelin?", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7b", "question": "What team did the Atlanta Braves defeat in the 1995 World Series?", "answer": "Cleveland Indians", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba00", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Honus Wagner play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a1", "question": "Who was the voice of Darth Vader in the original Star Wars movie?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc15c4469bb8041d07a08c", "question": "What does \"dim sum\" mean in English?", "answer": "Touching heart", "category": "general"}]